>> Jem Young: 现在不幸的是，如果我切换到那个用户，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So unfortunately now,
if I switch to that user,
我没有 root 用户访问权，我没有超级用户访问权。
I don't have root access,
I don't have super user access.
这就是 sudo 命令。
And that's referred to
as the sudo command.
sudo 代表超级用户，这很棒，很有道理。
sudo stands for super user do, which
is nice, cuz that actually makes sense.
所以每当你说 sudo ，超级用户就会这样做。
So whenever you say sudo,
you're like, super user do this.
因此，本质上，我正在以升级的特权运行该命令。
So essentially, I'm running that
command with escalated privileges.
但是首先，我需要给那个用户我刚刚创造了这些特权。
But first, I need to give that user
I just created those privileges.
例如，如果现在切换的话，我就不能这么做了。
For instance, if we switch over now,
I won't be able to do that much.
我将限制我的主目录 cutz ，但没有 root 用户访问权。
I'll be limited my home directory
cuz I have no root access.
所以我们要用这个用户的修改指令
So we're gonna use the user
mod command for it.
它会修改用户的
It's gonna modify the user.
我们会说用户 mod -aG sudo ，然后我们刚刚创建的用户名。
We're gonna say user mod -aG sudo,
and then the username we just created.
> > Jem Young: 所以我要说， usermod -aG sudo，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So I'm gonna say,
usermod -aG sudo,
然后哎呀，铃人，然后 jem， >> Jem Young: Cool，
and then oops, sudo, and then jem,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool,
所以我把杰姆加到这个超级用户群里
so I just added jem to
this super user's group.
> > Jem Young: 酷，我一直很清楚。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Cool, so
I keep hitting clear.
现在我想测试那个用户是否只是为了确保我所做的工作。
Now I wanna test that user out just to
make sure that what I did actually worked.
所以我们要换个用户
So we are gonna switch user.
因为那是苏和杰姆
For that, it's su, and, jem.
>> Jem Young: So 您的用户名。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So su your username.
然后我想确认我有超级用户的权限
And then I wanna verify that
I have superuser access.
有很多方法可以做但我想看看 auth 日志
There's lots of ways to do this, but
I like to take a look at the auth log,
现在是时候看看日志了
cuz it's a good time to look at logs.
所以如果我说猫 /var/
So if I say, cat /var/, let's see,
log， >> Jem Young: /auth.log
log,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: /auth.log,
它不会让我这么做的
it's not gonna let me do it.
因为查看这些日志需要超级用户访问权。
Because looking at these logs
requires super user access.
现在我要说的是除了我要说苏多
For now, I'm gonna say same
thing except I'm gonna say sudo.
它会问我密码，然后我就把那个日志记录了。
It's gonna ask me the password, and
there, I just catted that log file.
> > Jem Young: 每个人都能抓住我所做的一切吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Everybody catch what I did,
anybody behind?
很酷吧萨姆
Cool, Sam, yes?
>> Sam: 我没有这样的文件目录。
&gt;&gt; Sam: I'm getting no
such file directory.
你想说什么
What are you pointing to?
>> Jem Young: 我指的是 /var ，其实
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: I'm pointing to /var,
actually,
仅备份 /var/log/auth.log。
just go up, /var/log/auth.log.
每个 Ubuntu 分发都应该有一个 authlog。
Every Ubuntu distribution
should have an authlog.
如果没有的话那我们就在路上了
[LAUGH] If it doesn't,
we're way of course then.
>> Student : 正在获取我的用户不在 sudor的文件中。
&gt;&gt; Student: I'm getting that my
user is not in the sudor's file.
>> Jem Young: 好的，让我们后退。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Okay, so let's step back.
您是否运行了用户修改命令?
Did you run the user mod command?
>> 学生: 我做到了。
&gt;&gt; Student: I did.
>> Jem Young: 是同一个用户吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And it's the same user?
> > 学生: 我再做一次。
&gt;&gt; Student: I'll just run it again.
>> Jem Young: 如果所有其他用户都失败，请创建另一个用户。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: If all else fails,
make another user.
[ LAUGH] 如果该操作不起作用，请创建另一个服务器。
[LAUGH] And if that doesn't work,
create another server.
我就是这么做的 >> 类: [LAUGH]
That's what I do.
&gt;&gt; class: [LAUGH]
>> Jem Young: 假装第一个没有
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Pretend the first one didn't
发生了。 没事的没事的
happen.
It's fine.
我们都在同一层可以快速回电的地方
We all are at the same level where we
can catch back up pretty quickly at
这一点。
this point.
>> Jem Young: 作为速记，如果我试着逃跑，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: As a shorthand,
so if I try to run, actually,
我会做点不一样的事
I'll do something a little different,
I'll run less,
cuz 猫把整个文件的输出都转了，少给我一个页面。
cuz cat just dumps the entire file output,
less will give me a page.
再一次我也没和苏多指挥过
And once again,
I didn't run that command with sudo.
所以我喜欢这样做的捷径，因为它本质上是在说，
So a shortcut to do that is sudo Which I
love because it's essentially saying,
sudo，我运行的最后一个命令是 sudo 访问权。
sudo, the last command that I ran but
with sudo access.
这是一个速记，以防你试图运行需要 sudo 的东西
And it's a shorthand in case you ever
try to run something that requires sudo
许可权。
permission.
只需要 sudo !!，我将重新运行上一命令，并与 sudo重新运行。
Just sudo !!,
I'll rerun the last command with sudo.
现在我们越来越少了
And now we're running with less, so
我可以只使用箭头键来遍历文件。
I can traverse the file
with just the arrow keys.
而且比跑来的猫更友好些
And it's a little bit more
friendly than running cat,
把所有东西都转储到一个终端上
which just dumps everything to a terminal.
>> student2: 如何逃脱猫?
&gt;&gt; student2: How do you escape cat?
>> Jem Young: 好问题， q。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Good question, q.
为了逃避，就打 q ，你就会出来了。
To escape less, just hit q,
and you'll be back out.
问得好谢谢
Good question, thank you.
请你问我这些问题
And please,
ask me those types of questions,
我忘了我是用来做这些事的不是每个人都是这样
cuz I forget that I'm used to doing these
things and not everybody is the same way.
但现在我们在 authlog。
But now we're in authlog.
现在是安全话题的时候了
Now's a great time talk about security.
我说我们要谈安全明天可能更多
I said we're gonna talk about security,
probably more of it tomorrow.
但是您的认证日志只是一个尝试执行操作的人员的日志
But your authlog is just a log of
people that are attempting to do
或登录到服务器。
something on your server,
or log into your server.
既然我们的服务器已经升了一小时了
And since our server's been up for
maybe an hour or so,
根据你进来的地方你现在可以看到有人在试图
depending on where you came in at, you can
see right now that there are people trying
能主动进入我的服务器
to actively get in my server right now.
你在想我只是一个人
And you're thinking, I'm just some person.
[ LAUGH] 为什么这些黑客会试图进入我的服务器?
[LAUGH] Why would these hackers
try to get into my server?
因为有电脑在不停的运行他们在扫描整个
It's because there are computers running
constantly and they're scanning the entire
因特网，每个可能的 IP 地址组合。
Internet, every single possible
combination of IP address.
他们正在测试漏洞，他们正在测试较弱的密码，
And they're testing for vulnerabilities,
they're testing for weak passwords,
所以我们不使用密码
which is why we don't use passwords.
不管你有多聪明
It doesn't matter how clever you are,
也许最终会有人来测试
someone's probably gonna
test it eventually.
他们在测试您是否打开了易受攻击的端口 ?
They're testing, do you have ports
open that are vulnerable applications?
就像五号博尔顿在另一天利用，
So like that V Bolton
exploit the other day,
他们在测试你是否有这个运行
they're testing if you have that running.
他们在说我知道去那里
They're saying, I know to get into there.
如果你想知道这看起来像一帮小人
And if you're wondering,
this looks like a bunch of gibberish,
看看我的好东西哪来的
check out, let's see,
where's a good one for mine?
我们走吧 有一个无效的用户 appserver。
Here we go.
There's one, invalid user appserver.
因此有人尝试使用用户名 appserver 登录到我的服务器
So someone was trying to log into my
server using the username appserver
在端口 33710上。
on the port 33710.
我不知道那是什么港口
I don't know what port that is, but
我确定这是一个在港口上运行的着名应用。
I'm sure it's some well-known
application that runs on that port.
你可能在想，哇，我为冒犯这些人做了什么 ?
And you're probably thinking, wow,
what did I do to offend these people?
没事的大家都是你的人
Nothing, [LAUGH] everybody all the time
are you gonna try to break into your
服务器不断地运行。
server constantly.
你只是接受了这个
You just accept that's a given.
你不会离开你的前门的
You wouldn't leave your front door open.
这就是我们使用 SSH 密钥的原因。
That's why we use SSH keys.
据我们所知， SSH 密钥是不可破坏的。
SSH keys are,
as far as we know, unbreakable.
除非你把它拿走不然还有其他的弱点
Unless you give it away or
there's some other vulnerability.
如果我们想看看我们的服务器的真实情况
If we want to see a real time of
what's happening with our server,
我要用尾巴的命令
I'm gonna use the tail command.
其实我要开始了， > > Jem Young: 头，
Actually I'll start,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: head,
头会给我一个文件的最上面的 x 行
head will give me the top
x lines of a file.
所以我说， sudo， >> Jem Young: head，
So I will say, sudo,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: head,
>> Jem Young:
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And it's just gonna give
首先我想说 10 行任何给定的文件
me the first,
I wanna say ten lines of any given file.
所以，不是相反的，但它的必然是尾巴。
So the, not inverse, but
the corollary to that would be tail.
你在想
And you're wondering,
为什么会有那么多不同的方法来查看 Linux中的文件 ?
why are there so many different
ways to look at a file in Linux?
因为它们都很有用尤其是当你说的是
Because they're all useful, especially
when you're talking about megabytes of log
文件，你想从部分快速跳转到部分。
files, you wanna be able to quickly
jump from portion to portion.
头会给我这个文件的开始
head will give me what
the file started with,
它会给我带来的结果
tail will give me what it finished with.
所以如果我用尾巴， > > Jem Young: -f，
So if I use tail,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: -f, for follow,
这会使尾巴保持开放
this will keep tail open.
在每次对该日志文件执行新操作时，都会遵循此操作。
And it will follow along with every time
something new happens to to that log file.
它只会输出
It will just keep outputting.
例如，这件事就发生了。
And for instance, this just happened.
有人尝试在端口 3621 上连接到我的计算机
Someone just tried to connect
to my computer on port 3621 with
SSH 密钥无效。
an invalid SSH key.
如果你想对这个世界感到偏执并且人们会去找你
And if you wanna feel paranoid about the
world and that people are out to get you,
你就可以看到你的日志文件里有人试图闯进来
you can just tail your log file
watch people try to break in.
再说一次这不是私人的
Again, it's not personal.
尾巴 -f 可能是你学到的最有力的东西之一
tail -f is probably one of the most
powerful things you're gonna learn
在调试的时候
when it comes to debugging.
因为服务器上的一切你都想把它记录下来
Because everything on a server,
you wanna log it somewhere.
因为当事情出错的时候，你就不知道为什么了。
Because when things go wrong,
you'll have no idea why.
所以你想把你的档案记录在某个地方最后他们会被清理干净
So you wanna log all your file somewhere,
and eventually they get cleaned up.
但是跟踪日志文件和
But tailing a log file and
然后连接到位于不同终端或外壳的服务器。
then connecting to a server at
a different terminal or shell and
了解正在发生的事情是我们拥有的最强大的调试工具之一。
understanding what's happening is one of
the most powerful debugging tools we have.
它等价于在 JavaScript 控制台中记录所有内容。
It's equivalent to in JavaScript
console logging everything.
所以尾巴 -f 是一个要记住的指令，要离开这里，只需要 Ctrl+C 。
So tail -f is a command to remember,
and to get out of here, just Ctrl+C.
这将停止跟踪该日志文件。
And that will stop
following that log file.
>> Jem Young: 好的，我们知道我们的服务器很安全，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: All right, so
we know that our server's secure,
我们的人还没进入呢
cuz people haven't gotten in yet.
库兹我还在这里
Cuz I'm still here.
如果我想去我的家
If I wanna go to my home directory,
就像在我们的麦克机器 cd 和 pwd上一样
same as on our Mac machines, cd, and pwd.
我在我的家里
And I'm in my home directory.
这是我的游戏目录，不管这里发生什么事都不重要。
This is kind of my play directory, it
doesn't matter to much what happens here.
第二个，我们会创建我们的 ssh 目录和其他的东西
In a second, we'll create our ssh
directory and all sorts of other things so
我们可以用 ssh 的方式
we can ssh in.
但是现在，感觉自由，你可以玩这个目录
But for now, feel free, you can
play around with this directory and
做你想做的事
do kind of whatever you want.
它不会影响更大的系统， cutz 是您的主目录。
It's not gonna affect the greater system,
cuz it's your home directory.